Soyeon Kim

Seongnam-si, Gyeonggi-do, South Korea

Tel: +82-10-9650-7366 / Email: slmlsy2552@gmail.com / Website:

Summary Statement

Counseling psychology MA graduate experienced in research and counseling practice. Familiar with various
methodologies such as SEM, multi-regression analysis, HLM, Meta-analysis, etc. Proficient in using SPSS,
AMOS, MIX, HLM, etc. Research interests include Working Adults, Mental Illness, Quantitative analysis,
Marginalization, Career development.

Research Experience

- [Master's Thesis] Attachment styles and burnout: The mediating role of basic psychological needs satisfaction
 - Primary author. The research was conducted using SEM on a sample of Korean working adults. Responsibilities included establishing hypotheses, elaborating and conducting the survey, data analysis and writing the manuscript.
- Applying the Demand-Control Support Model on Burnout in Students: A Meta-Analysis (Under Review)
 - Primary author. Responsibilities included interpreting the results, deriving the discussion and writing the Results and Discussion section.
- The Moderating Effect of Student-Teacher Relationship: A Cross-Level Analysis Using Hierarchical Linear Modeling (Under Review)
 - Secondary author. Responsibilities included supporting data processing, data analysis using the HLM
 program, interpreting the results, and deriving the discussion as well as writing the Methods and
 Literature review section.
- The Job Demands-Resources Model in Academic Burnout (Under Review)
 - Tertiary author. Supported writing the Literature review and conducting the English correction.
- Volitional Competence and Academic Burnout: Latent Mean Differences across groups (Work in Progress)
 - Primary author. Responsibilities included data processing, data analysis using SEM, interpreting the results, deriving the discussion, and writing the Methods, Results and Discussion sections.
- Coping strategies and Posttraumatic Growth: A Meta-Analysis (Work in Progress)
 - Secondary author. Responsibilities included literature search, data-coding, data analysis using the Mix program, and writing Literature review section.

Clinical Experience

Sep. 2018– Aug. 2020 Counselor, Catholic University Graduate School Counseling Center

Duties: Intake Interview, Psychological Assessment(MMPI, WAIS etc.), Counseling of Catholic University students

Educational History

Sep. 2018 – Aug. 2020 **M.A. Psychology**

Bucheon, South Korea

The Catholic University of Korea Major: Counseling Psychology

Honors Thesis: Attachment styles and burnout: the mediating role of basic

psychological needs satisfaction

GPA: 4.5 out of 4.5

Mar. 2007 – Feb. 2012 B.A Spanish Language and Literature

Seoul, South Korea

Korea University

Major: Spanish Language and Literature

Minor: Art and Design GPA: 3.45 out of 4.5 Major GPA: 3.74

Sep. 2008 – Dec. 2008 Overseas study (exchange program)

Salamanca, Spain

University of Salamanca

Relevant Coursework

Area	Title of the course	GPA
Psychological Measurement	Psychological Assessment	4.5/4.5
Research Methods	Research Methods in Psychology	4.5/4.5
	Multivariate Research Methods	4.5/4.5
Counseling Psychology	Cognitive-Behavior Therapy	4.5/4.5
	Counseling and Psychotherapy	4.5/4.5
	Multicultural Counseling	4.5/4.5
	Person-Centered Therapy	4.5/4.5
	Object Relation Theory and Counseling	4.5/4.5
Counseling Psychology Practicum	Therapeutic Interview Practicum	4.5/4.5
Developmental Psychology	Emotional Development	4.5/4.5

Scholarships

2011 (Spring)	Korea University Family Scholarship (\$1,000)
2010 (Spring)	Scholarship by Alumni Association of Dept. of Spanish Language & Literature
	(\$1,500)
2008 (Fall)	KU Student Exchange Program Scholarship (\$2,500)
2008 (Spring)	Study Scholarships (\$2,700)
2007 (Spring)	Special Scholarship for Freshmen (\$2,600)

Membership in Professional Association

Sep. 2018 – present	Member of Korean Psychological Association
Nov. 2017- present	Member of Toastmasters International

Professional Experience

May. 2015 – Mar. 2018 **P&G Korea**

Seoul, South Korea

Market Strategy and Planning Manager

- [Awards] P&G Power of You award (2016, 2017)
- Luxury Cosmetics (SK-II) Market Planner: Single ownership of stock, sales plan, budget, new initiatives launching
- eCommerce sales manager (brands: Pampers, Oral-B, H&S): Sales plan execution, negotiate with customers

Aug. 2013 – Aug. 2014 Samsung Electronics Mexico

Queretaro, Mexico

Procurement Manager

• Procure raw materials from international and local vendors. Develop new vendors and procurement system

Jan. 2012 – Jun. 2013 **KT&G**

Seoul, South Korea

Sales Manager

• Product management and advertising operations in retail stores. Consumer and market behavior research

Test Scores

- GRE: Verbal 163 (93 percentile), Quant 169 (95 percentile), Writing 3.5 (39 percentile)
- TOEFL(best score): 108 (Reading 29, Listening 28, Speaking 26, Writing 25)

Languages

- Native Korean Speaker
- · Proficient in English and Spanish

References

Boyoung Kim (Assistant Professor, Catholic University) Kumlan Yu (Professor, Catholic University) herena.kim@catholic.ac.kr kyu@catholic.ac.kr